Guide to the Russell Hoban Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Russell Hoban papers
1952-2011
GEN MSS 1436
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
26.5
(87 boxes) + 1 art
The Russell Hoban Papers, which span from 1952 to 2011, contain writings from throughout Russell Hoban's lifetime including novels, children's books, poetry, and opera librettos. The papers also contain clippings, ephemera, photographs, audiovisual materials, and electronic media related to Hoban's life and work.
Hoban, Russell, 1925-2011
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 68, 74, 77, 86-87 (digital media): Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 69, 73, 78, 85 (audiovisual materials): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Glenn Horowitz Bookseller, Inc. on the Jockey Hollow Fund and on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2016.
Arrangement
Organized into five series: I. Writings, 1956-2011. II. Correspondence, 1963-2011. III.Writings on Russell and Lillian Hoban, 1964-2002. IV. Diaries, 1956-2005. V. Artwork, circa 1952-1980.
Russell Hoban (1925-2011)
Russell Hoban (1925-2011) was an American author who wrote novels, poetry, operatic librettos, and children's books. Notably, he collaborated with illustrator and author Lillian Hoban, to whom he was married from 1944-1972, on the "Frances the Badger" children's books.
Related Materials
Russell Hoban Collection. Related materials: Lillian Hoban Papers (GEN MSS 1199). Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of writings, drawings, posters, correspondence, other papers, and audiovisual materials related to the life and work of Russell Hoban. The writings and drawings document Hoban's career as a novelist, librettist, and children's book author including the Frances books he collaborated on with his former wife, Lillian Hoban.
Children's literature, American -- 20th Century; American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Audiocassettes; Audiovisual materials; Photographs; Born digital; Videocassettes; Authors, American -- United States -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- United States -- 21st century; Hoban, Russell, 1925-2011; Hoban, Lillian, 1925-1998
- Writings, 1956-2011; Series I; 36.83; (79 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Materials within this series maintain the original physical organization found at time of acquisition with the exception of some oversized materials.
  Scope and Contents
  Contains materials related to Russell Hoban's writings. Materials within this series are organized under seven headings: children's books, scripts and librettos, poems, short stories, essays and short fiction, novels, and unsorted notes, writings, and ephemera.
  - Children's books
    - What Does it Do and How Does It Work?--original sketches, circa 1959 (Box 1)
    - What Does it Do and How Does It Work?--proof copy, circa 1959 (Box 1)
    - The Atomic Submarine--draft, circa 1960 (Box 1)
    - The Atomic Submarine--draft, circa 1960 (Box 1)
    - Drafts for Children's Books, circa 1963 (Box 1)
    - The Mystery of the Wag-on-Mall, 1964 (Box 1)
    - The Tin Prince, 1964 (Box 1)
    - Television for Frances, 1964 (Box 1)
    - The Story of Hester Mouse--notes and drafts, circa 1965 (Box 1)
    - The Tin Bulldog & the Brown Sparrow, 1965 (Box 1)
    - A Birthday for Frances, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Frances Stories--unfinished and unpublished, 1967-1993 (Box 1)
    - Three O'Clock Place--drafts, notes, and pictures, circa 1967-1993 (Box 1)
    - Claudia and the King of the Wood--early notes and drafts, circa 1968 (Box 1)
    - Claudia and the King of the Wood--drafts, circa 1968 (Box 1)
    - Claudia and the King of the Wood--drafts, circa 1968 (Box 2)
    - Claudia and the King of the Wood--Chapters 1-7, circa 1968 (Box 2)
    - The Mole Family's Christmas, 1968 (Box 2)
    - Best Friends for Frances, 1968 (Box 2)
    - A Thread to Find--unpublished children's book and notes, 1968 (Box 2)
    - Paul and His Father--unpublished stories, 1968 (Box 2)
    - A Thread to Find--unpublished draft, 1968 (Box 2)
    - Harvey Muskrat's Motorboat, 1968 (Box 2)
    - Dinner at Alberta's, 1969 (Box 2)
    - A Bargain for Frances, 1969 (Box 2)
    - Emmett Otter's Jug-Band, 1969 (Box 2)
    - A Bargain for Frances, 1969 (Box 2)
    - The Golden Grasshopper, circa 1970 (Box 2)
    - Dinner at Alberta's, 1970 (Box 2)
    - David Whale--drafts, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
    - Egg Thoughts and other Frances Songs, 1970-1972 (Box 2)
    - The Sea-Thing Child, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Letitia Rabbit's String Song, 1970 (Box 2)
    - The Sea-Thing Child--draft, 1971 (Box 2)
    - La Corona and the Tin Frog, 1971 (Box 2)
    - How Tom Beat Captain Najork--draft, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Victorian Inventions postcard--inspiration for Captain Najork, 1971 (Box 2)
    - David Whale and the Kraken--drafts, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Letitia Rabbit's String Song, 1971 (Box 3)
    - David Whale and the Kraken, circa 1971 (Box 3)
    - The Sea-Thing Child--drafts and pictures, 1972 (Box 3)
    - The Fiddler Crab, 1972 (Box 3)
    - Unpublished notes and drafts, circa 1973 (Box 3)
    - Letitia Rabbit's String Song, circa 1973 (Box 3)
    - Blues for Frances, 1973 (Box 3)
    - How Tom Beat Captain Najork and His Hired Sportsmen; A Near Thing For Captain Najork, circa 1974 (Box 3)
    - 10 What?, circa 1974 (Box 3)
    - The Lemon-Pip Place, 1974 (Box 3)
    - The Dancing Tigers and Other Savage Stories, 1974 (Box 3)
    - The Dancing Tigers and Other Savage Stories, 1974 (Box 3)
    - The Twenty Elephant Restaurant, 1975 (Box 3)
    - The Twenty Elephant Restaurant, 1975 (Box 3)
    - The Svalomino Affair, 1975 (Box 3)
    - The Svalomino Affair, 1975 (Box 3)
    - The Ghost of Baron Najork, 1975 (Box 3)
    - Aunt Fidget Wonkham-Strong Najork's Monster Rally, 1975 (Box 3)
    - Bill Cats Little Brown Bottle, 1975 (Box 3)
    - With Lego Through the Jungle, 1976 (Box 3)
    - With Lego Through the Jungle, 1976 (Box 3)
    - Arthur's New Power, 1976 (Box 3)
    - Arthur's New Power, 1976 (Box 3)
    - The Marzipan Pig--drafts, 1976 (Box 3)
    - The Marzipan Pig, 1976 (Box 3)
    - Assorted handwritten notes, 1976 (Box 3)
    - The Tisbury Toad--draft, 1977 (Box 3)
    - Flat Cat--script, 1977-1979 (Box 3)
    - Four in the Morning--drafts, circa 1960-1963 (Box 4)
    - Four in the Morning--drafts, circa 1960-1963 (Box 4)
    - Four in the Morning--drafts, circa 1960-1963 (Box 4)
    - Four in the Morning--drafts, circa 1960-1963 (Box 4)
    - The Mouse and His Child--screenplay, undated (Box 4)
    - Pun with Numbers, undated (Box 4)
    - The Tisbury Toads, undated (Box 4)
    - Numbering Around, undated (Box 4)
    - Listening Lewis, undated (Box 5)
    - Always Say Hello to the Twelfth Chinese Boy, undated (Box 5)
    - Tom and the Time Tree, undated (Box 5)
    - Random notes and drafts for children's books, undated (Box 5)
    - Tools--notes and drafts, undated (Box 5)
    - Emmet Otter's Jug-Band Christmas, undated (Box 5)
    - The Sling and the Flute, undated (Box 5)
    - Crazy Pony--proof copy, undated (Box 5)
    - Mr. Boor--handwritten draft, undated (Box 5)
    - The Sea-Thing Child--final print copy for reprint, 1999 (Box 5)
    - Jim's Lion--drafts, 1998-2001 (Box 5)
    - Trouble on Thunder Mountain, 1997 (Box 5)
    - A Bed Time for the Scalybums, 1996 (Box 5)
    - Jim and Hendryk--book/CD-ROM script, 1996 (Box 5)
    - A Bad Time for Scalybums, 1996 (Box 5)
    - Mawners--children's poem, 1996 (Box 5)
    - Monster film, 1990 (Box 5)
    - Jim Hedgehog and the Lonesome Tower, circa 1990 (Box 5)
    - Jim Hedgehog and the Pantomime Horse Dept., 1989 (Box 5)
    - The Ups and Downs of Adam Mole, 1989 (Box 5)
    - Adam Again/Adam Wolf, 1989 (Box 5)
    - Jim Hedgehog's Strange Recorder, 1989 (Box 5)
    - Jim Hedgehog artwork--exchange with Jane Nissen, 1989 (Box 5)
    - The Court of the Winged Serpent, 1989-1994 (Box 5)
    - The Court of the Winged Serpent, 1989 (Box 5)
    - The Secret of the Emerald Key, 1989 (Box 5)
    - Jim Hedgehog's Midnight Saxophone, 1989 (Box 5)
    - Jim Hedgehog's Supernatural Christmas, 1989 (Box 5)
    - The Boy in the Boat, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Jim Hedgehog--drafts, 1988-1989 (Box 6)
    - Jim Hedgehog's Supernatural Christmas, 1988 (Box 6)
    - Jim Hedgehog's Midnight Saxophone, 1988 (Box 6)
    - Monsters--drafts, 1987-1988 (Box 6)
    - The Ghost Horse of Genghis Khan, 1987 (Box 6)
    - The Sling and the Flute--drafts, 1987 (Box 6)
    - The Water Flower, 1982 (Box 6)
    - Joram Vanderstander, 1981 (Box 6)
    - Powders Series--drafts, 1981 (Box 6)
    - They Come From Aargh!, 1980 (Box 6)
    - The Rain Door--drafts and notes, 1979 (Box 6)
    - Illustration notes for "The Great Fruit Gum Robbery", 1979 (Box 6)
    - The Ghost of Jimson Crow--drafts and notes, 1979 (Box 6)
    - Serpent Tower--drafts and notes, 1979 (Box 6)
    - The Dancing Tiger--notes, ca. 1979 (Box 6)
    - Ace Dragon Ltd., 1978 (Box 6)
    - Turtle Diary: A Book at Bedtime, 1978 (Box 6)
    - Mouse and His Child--notes and letter, ca. 1988 (Box 7)
    - Miranda and Caliban--script, drafts, notes, 1987 (Box 7)
  - Scripts and librettos
    - People of the Forest--libretto, 1985 (Box 7)
    - People of the Forest--libretto, drafts, notes, 1986 (Box 7)
    - People of the Forest--libretto draft, 1984 (Box 7)
    - Carrier Frequency--cuttings, photos, publicity, 1985-1986 (Box 8)
    - Carrier Frequency--play, notes, letters, 1984-1999 (Box 8)
    - Come and Find Me--script drafts, 1980 (Box 8)
    - Cathexis--script, 1979 (Box 8)
    - The Lion of Jachin Boaz--script, 1976 (Box 8)
    - Kleinzeit--script, 1974 (Box 9)
    - Mouse and His Child--screenplay by Carol Mon Pere, 1975 (Box 9)
    - Kleinzeit--script, circa 1974 (Box 9)
    - Kleinzeit--screenplay, circa 1974 (Box 9)
    - Kleinzeit--screenplay, circa 1974 (Box 9)
    - Kleinzeit--script, circa 1974 (Box 10)
    - Saturday with Miss Daphne and Lemon Drops, circa 1971 (Box 10)
    - The Mouse and His Child--adaptation by Tamsin Oglesby, 1990 (Box 10)
    - The Mouse and His Child--adaptation, 1990 (Box 10)
    - My Lost Noah's Ark--script, 2000 (Box 10)
    - By the River in the Mind--radio play, 1999 (Box 10)
    - How Tom Beat Captain Najork--screenplay, 1999 (Box 10)
    - Ariosto--script, notes, 1997 (Box 10)
    - Gina Destina--script, 1996 (Box 10)
    - The Second Mrs. Kong--libretto, 1996 (Box 10)
    - Fantasia on a Departed Cavalier--libretto, 1995 (Box 10)
    - Ariosto--script, notes, 1995 (Box 11)
    - The Second Mrs. Kong--libretto, notes, 1994 (Box 11)
    - The Second Mrs. Kong--reviews, cuttings, libretto, notes, 1994-1995 (Box 11)
    - The Second Mrs. Kong--programs, letters, scores, 1994 (Box 11)
    - The Lion--screenplay, 1993 (Box 11)
    - It's a Long Way Anywhere--script, 1993 (Box 11)
    - Mpingo--drafts, notes, letters, 1991-1992 (Box 11)
    - The Vermeer Girl and Kong--drafts, notes, letters, 1991 (Box 12)
    - Some Episodes in the History of Miranda and Caliban, 1990 (Box 12)
    - Soonchild--stage play, drafts, 1990 (Box 12)
    - Miranda and Caliban--libretto, notes, 1990 (Box 12)
    - Soonchild--script, drafts, 1989-1990 (Box 12)
    - The Marzipan Pig--screenplay, 1988 (Box 12)
    - Riddley Walker--stageplay, 1986-1993 (Box 13)
    - Program for Riddley Walker, 1986 (Box 13)
    - The Hynd of the Wood photocopy, circa 1986 (Box 13)
    - Riddley Walker--stageplay, scripts, 1986 (Box 13)
    - Riddley Walker--stageplay, 1986 (Box 13)
    - Riddley Walker--stageplay, 1986 (Box 13)
    - Riddley Walker--stageplay, 1986 (Box 14)
    - Riddley Walker--stageplay, 1986 (Box 14)
    - Riddley Walker--stageplay, 1986 (Box 14)
    - Riddley Walker--stageplay, 1986 (Box 14)
    - Riddley Walker--stageplay, 1986 (Box 15)
    - Riddley Walker--stageplay, 1986 (Box 15)
    - Riddley Walker--stageplay, 1986 (Box 15)
    - Riddley Walker--stageplay, 1986 (Box 15)
    - Riddley Walker--stageplay, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Poems
    - Dragons Made of Gingerbread and other poems, undated (Box 19)
    - Poems entitled "New Poems, 1996-2001 (Box 19)
    - Dragons poems, 1994 (Box 19)
    - Orpheus, Eurydice, Hermes, 1984 (Box 19)
    - Seven Views of Zarmin poems, 1989 (Box 19)
    - The Space Voyage of Drlzi Nngh, 1983-1989 (Box 19)
    - On the Krung, 1983 (Box 19)
    - Poetry and notes, circa 1978 (Box 19)
    - I Could Win the Title and other poems, 1972 (Box 19)
    - The Fountain Lady and other poems, 1972 (Box 19)
    - Notes for "Thames Where, Thames When", 1971 (Box 19)
    - The Ageing Lover and other poems, 1971 (Box 19)
    - Egg Thoughts and other poems, 1970 (Box 19)
    - Poems and drafts, 1970 (Box 19)
    - Mulberry Close poems, circa 1970 (Box 19)
    - Admission: One Shilling and other poems, 1969 (Box 19)
    - Poems on aging and wisdom, 1969 (Box 19)
    - King Ashurbanipal and other poems, 1968 (Box 19)
    - I Saw Two Stone Lions and other poems, 1968 (Box 19)
    - Crazy John and other poems, 1967 (Box 19)
    - My Lost Noah's Ark--poem and notes, circa 1967 (Box 19)
    - London poem and notes, 1966-1967 (Box 19)
    - The Pedalling Man--poem and drafts, circa 1966-1978 (Box 19)
    - Poetry pre-1967 plus unused "Pedalling Man" material, circa 1966 (Box 20)
    - La Corona poems, 1965 (Box 20)
    - Shuttered Windows and other poems, 1961-1962 (Box 20)
    - Lost Moon and other poems, 1962-1965 (Box 20)
  - Short stories
    - The Truth Room--sketch, undated (Box 20)
    - Message in a Klein Bottle, 2011 (Box 20)
    - My Trip with Arabella and other stories, 2011 (Box 20)
    - Situation 37, 2004 (Box 20)
    - Severine, 1999 (Box 20)
    - When Crazy Horse..., 1999 (Box 20)
    - Nightmare on Mount Caburn, 1998 (Box 20)
    - Out There, 1998 (Box 20)
    - Like a Circle in a Spiral, 1997 (Box 20)
    - Metropolitan magazine featuring "Peepshow Love", 1997 (Box 20)
    - Cuts, 1996-1997 (Box 20)
    - The Wall at All Hallows, 1996 (Box 20)
    - Be Jubilant, My Feet, 1995 (Box 20)
    - Man's Reach, 1995 (Box 20)
    - Busenello's Ritornello, 1995 (Box 20)
    - Dali Girl--story, score, drafts, 1994 (Box 20)
    - Eurydice's Return, 1994 (Box 20)
    - My Peepshow Love, 1993 (Box 20)
    - Short story collection, 1993-1996 (Box 21)
    - The Vermeer Girl and Kong, 1991 (Box 21)
    - Kong's Diary--sketch, 1991 (Box 21)
    - My Night with Leonie, 1991 (Box 21)
    - My Peepshow Love, circa 1991 (Box 21)
    - Kristal Grotte--story, notes, 1990 (Box 21)
    - There and Back, 1990 (Box 21)
    - Moongoer's Christmas, 1989 (Box 21)
    - Last Rendezvous Zarmni, 1984 (Box 21)
    - The Fool's Tarot, 1989 (Box 21)
    - The Man with the Dagger--Granta version, 1988 (Box 21)
    - Schwartz, 1988 (Box 21)
    - Shadows of Yester--story, drafts, 1988 (Box 21)
    - The Jumble Stall/Owl Woman--early draft, 1988 (Box 21)
    - Corpano--draft, 1987 (Box 21)
    - Fugue, 1987 (Box 21)
    - Door--story, drafts, 1986 (Box 21)
    - Dream Woman--notes, story, 1985 (Box 21)
    - Moongoer's Christmas, 1984 (Box 21)
    - Orpheus and Eurydice--dialogue, 1984 (Box 21)
    - What the Bomb Said, 1984 (Box 21)
    - Blue Orpheus--fragments, 1984 (Box 21)
    - The Man with the Dagger--draft, story, 1984 (Box 22)
    - Perseus and Fay Wray--sketch, 1984 (Box 22)
    - Fan Freak--drafts, 1984 (Box 22)
    - Moongoer--drafts, 1983 (Box 22)
    - Your Place, 1983 (Box 22)
    - Show Me Yours, 1983 (Box 22)
    - Fragments of a Lament, 1983 (Box 22)
    - Moongoer--drafts, 1982-1983 (Box 22)
    - The Treadmill Owls, 1980 (Box 22)
    - The Wincer Boise, 1980 (Box 22)
    - Various sketches, 1977-1985 (Box 22)
    - The No of Smoking, 1977 (Box 22)
    - Falling Through the Front, 1977 (Box 22)
    - Jack of Windows, 1977 (Box 22)
    - Remember Still the Flowering..., 1976 (Box 22)
    - Noochivenska Nonsense Book, 1975 (Box 22)
    - The Three-Story Pagoda, 1974 (Box 22)
    - Sea Stones, 1971 (Box 22)
    - The Drawing of the Heath, 1970 (Box 22)
    - King Asurbanipal, 1968-1970 (Box 22)
    - The Time Painter, circa 1968 (Box 22)
    - The Tomboy--story, draft, circa 1964 (Box 22)
    - The Brown Leather Bag--draft, circa 1963 (Box 22)
    - Dionysis at the Ball Park--notes, sketches, circa 1960 (Box 22)
  - Essays and short fiction
    - Meditation on Death, undated (Box 24)
    - A Place to Be, undated (Box 24)
    - Various published essays, undated (Box 24)
    - Introduction/foreword to Walter De La Mare's "Missing", 2006 (Box 24)
    - Mnemosyne in the Underworld, 1999 (Box 24)
    - Opening address to the Walter De La Mare Society, 1998 (Box 24)
    - Essay about Quentin Blake, 1997 (Box 24)
    - "Wilde Pomegranates" essay in Children's Literature in Education, 1996-1997 (Box 24)
    - Partly Now, Partly Remembered, 1996 (Box 24)
    - Bury My Heart at Auschwitz, 1995 (Box 24)
    - On the Bearable Beastliness of Being, 1993 (Box 24)
    - "1975"--essay about time, place, and Riddley Walker, 1992 (Box 24)
    - Essay on Walter De La Mare, 1992 (Box 24)
    - Draft of Walter De La Mare speech, 1992 (Box 24)
    - Blighter's Rock, 1990 (Box 24)
    - On Unfinished Starts, 1988 (Box 24)
    - Certain Obsessions, Certain Ideas--Granta version, 1985 (Box 24)
    - Article on working with Impact Theatre Group, 1984 (Box 24)
    - I, That Was a Child, 1984 (Box 24)
    - The Moment Under the Moment--essay, sketches, 1984-1991 (Box 24)
    - Talk on myth, 1983 (Box 24)
    - Essay on the radio and music, 1983 (Box 24)
    - Footplacers, London Transport Owls, Wincer-Boise, 1981 (Box 24)
    - Footplacers, London Transport Owls, Wincer-Boise, 1981 (Box 24)
    - Don Quixote essay, 1980 (Box 24)
    - A Little as Plaining about Riddley Walker, 1980 (Box 24)
    - Mnemosyne, Teen Taals, and Tottenham Court Road, circa 1980 (Box 24)
    - Pan Lives, By the Way at the Inn, Portknockie, 1979 (Box 25)
    - Grimm introduction, 1976 (Box 25)
    - Stories That Grew Up With Me, 1976 (Box 25)
    - Yes, It's a Children's Book, 1976 (Box 25)
    - Puffin Post feat. essay on speaking objects, circa 1976 (Box 25)
    - "Teacher Be Good" essay on creativity, 1976 (Box 25)
    - Listonel workshop talks, 1976 (Box 25)
    - Description of writing process, 1976 (Box 25)
    - Recent thoughts on being and writing, 1972 (Box 25)
    - Lecture on awareness and artistic representation, 1972 (Box 25)
    - Lecture on learning to read--for children lit conference, 1972 (Box 25)
    - Teachers' notes for "The Mouse", 1971 (Box 25)
    - Thames Where, Thames When--draft, 1971 (Box 25)
    - Lecture on "Hearing the Silence", 1971 (Box 25)
    - Lecture on various things, 1970 (Box 25)
    - Rose Hip Tea at Cranks and other sketches, 1970 (Box 25)
    - Schoolday memoir rough draft, 1968 (Box 25)
    - Article about "The Mouse and His Child", circa 1968 (Box 25)
    - Essay on acting, 1965 (Box 25)
    - 54th Street: Where the Magic Starts, circa 1965 (Box 25)
    - On Machinery and the Morality of Beauty and other drafts, circa 1965 (Box 25)
    - Article on boxing--drafts, circa 1964 (Box 25)
    - "On Teaching Art" essay, circa 1960 (Box 25)
    - In Defense of Buying Boats, 1959 (Box 25)
  - Novels
    - The Mouse and His Child--original artwork, undated (Box 26)
    - The Mouse and His Child--annotated draft, undated (Box 26)
    - The Mouse and His Child--early draft, undated (Box 26)
    - The Mouse and His Child--draft, undated (Box 26)
    - The Mouse and His Child--draft, 1967 (Box 26)
    - The Mouse and His Child--final draft, 1967 (Box 26)
    - The Mouse and His Child--master proof, 1967 (Box 27)
    - The Mouse and His Child--part 10 notes, 1966 (Box 27)
    - The Mouse and His Child--chapter drafts and notes, 1966 (Box 27)
    - The Mouse and His Child--chapter draft, 1966 (Box 27)
    - The Mouse and His Child--draft, 1966 (Box 27)
    - The Mouse and His Child--chapter drafts, 1966 (Box 27)
    - The Mouse and His Child--opening drafts, 1966 (Box 27)
    - The Mouse and His Child--draft, 1966 (Box 28)
    - The Mouse and His Child--draft, 1966 (Box 28)
    - The Mouse and His Child--draft, 1965 (Box 28)
    - The Mouse and His Child--in-depth notes, 1964-1966 (Box 28)
    - The Mouse and His Child--notes, 1964 (Box 28)
    - The Mouse and His Child--draft, 1963 (Box 28)
    - The Mouse and His Child--draft, 1963 (Box 28)
    - The Mouse and His Child--draft, 1963 (Box 28)
    - Riddley Walker--opening, 1978 (Box 29)
    - St. Eustace--notes and Eusa story, 1978 (Box 29)
    - Riddley Walker--opening, 1978 (Box 29)
    - Eusa story, 1978 (Box 29)
    - Riddley Walker--opening, 1977-1978 (Box 29)
    - Riddley Walker--notes, 1977-1978 (Box 29)
    - Riddley Walker--opening, 1977 (Box 29)
    - Riddley Walker--notes and drafts, 1976-1977 (Box 29)
    - Riddley Walker--opening, 1976-1977 (Box 29)
    - Riddley Walker--notes, 1976 (Box 29)
    - Riddley Walker--draft, 1976-1977 (Box 29)
    - Riddley Walker--notes, 1976 (Box 29)
    - Riddley Walker--notes, 1975-1976 (Box 29)
    - Notes, letters, and photographs on Punch and Judy for Riddley Walker, 1974-1975 (Box 30)
    - Riddley Walker--opening, 1974 (Box 30)
    - Riddley Walker--early reworkings of Eusa tale, 1974 (Box 30)
    - Riddley Walker--notes, 1974 (Box 30)
    - Sketches of Punch for Riddley Walker, circa 1974 (Box 30)
    - Turtle Diary--draft, circa 1975 (Box 30)
    - Kleinzeit--segments and notes, 1972 (Box 30)
    - Kleinzeit--draft, ca. 1972 (Box 30)
    - Lion of Jachin-Boaz photos, undated (Box 30)
    - Lion of Jachin-Boaz, 1972 (Box 30)
    - The Return of Manny Rat, 1972 (Box 31)
    - The Return of Manny Rat--draft, 1972 (Box 31)
    - The Return of Manny Rat--draft and notes, 1971 (Box 31)
    - The Return of Manny Rat--photos, ca. 1971 (Box 31)
    - The Return of Manny Rat--draft and notes, 1969-1972 (Box 31)
    - The Return of Manny Rat--draft, 1969 (Box 31)
    - The Return of Manny Rat--notes and sources, circa 1969 (Box 31)
    - The Return of Manny Rat--drafts, 1968-1969 (Box 31)
    - The Return of Manny Rat--Chapter 1 notes, 1968 (Box 31)
    - The Return of Manny Rat--notes and drafts, 1967-1969 (Box 31)
    - Riddley Walker--draft (pg. 80-109), 1978 - July (Box 32)
    - Riddley Walker--notes, 1978 June - August (Box 32)
    - Riddley Walker--drafts and notes, 1978 June - September (Box 32)
    - Riddley Walker--Lorna Section, 1978 April - October (Box 32)
    - Riddley Walker--notes, 1978 October (Box 32)
    - Riddley Walker--draft, 1979 April - June (Box 32)
    - Riddley Walker--notes and drafts, 1979 July (Box 32)
    - Riddley Walker--notes, 1979 August (Box 32)
    - Riddley Walker--notes and drafts, 1979 August (Box 32)
    - Riddley Walker--late draft, 1979 November (Box 32)
    - Riddley Walker--early draft (printed?), 1980 March - April (Box 32)
    - Riddley Walker--plan / synopsis (early?), undated (Box 32)
    - Riddley Walker--notes, undated (Box 32)
    - Riddley Walker--early drafts and notes, undated (Box 32)
    - St. Eustace and Eusa--notes and drafts (late?), undated (Box 32)
    - Eusa story (late?), undated (Box 32)
    - Boar picture and Ecclesiastes quote, for Riddley Walker?, undated (Box 32)
    - Draft of Riddley Walker, 1974-1976; (3 folders) (Box 33)
    - Draft of Riddley Walker, 1978 April - August; (3 folders) (Box 34)
      Contains notes and annotations.
    - Riddley Walker final, 1979 September - November; (2 folders) (Box 34)
    - Riddley Walker--draft, 1979 September - November (Box 35)
    - Riddley Walker--proof, 1980 February (Box 35)
    - Afterword, glossary and notes for Riddley Walker Expanded Edition, 1998 February - November (Box 35)
    - Unsorted notes and drafts, undated (Box 36)